This is Trigun.
guitar solo
Vash? Vash?
Wake up! Quick!
Oh, Vash.
What, Rem?
Where the hell am I?
What have I...
What have I become?
Thank you so much for all your help.
He might not have made it otherwise.
Think nothing of it.
If you need anything else, all you have
to do is ask. I will. Thank you again.
Oh, you're awake.
Well, already that's an improvement.
I was worried about you.
You must be hungry.
I'll fix you some soup.
Where are we?
It's a small village, about 200
aisles from the town of Valar.
There's a lot of very kind
people living in this town.
They let us stay at this house
so we could care for your wounds.
Do you remember anything?
You've been asleep since we
arrived, for ten days straight now.
Here.
It's my own recipe.
Drink up.
It's good for healing.
I remember.
I remember all of it.
Oh, hey! I almost forgot.
I need to be somewhere.
I better hurry.
I'll be back later, kay?
See ya!
Make sure you drink all your soup, okay?
Oh, Vash.
Miss Meryl?
Miss Meryl? Huh?
How is your friend doing?
Is he feeling any better?
Oh, much better, thank you.
He finally regained consciousness.
In fact, if he keeps healing at this
rate, he should be up and about real soon.
That's wonderful, dear.
I'm happy to hear that.
Oh, dear!
I'm sorry about that! Huh?
Mr.
Vash is awake?
Gee, Meryl, that's wonderful news.
Yeah. That's great.
You must be excited.
Uh, oh, yeah, that reminds me.
Here you go.
It's today's wages.
I'm sorry about this, Millie.
Making you do all the work
by yourself, it's not fair.
Don't worry about it.
I always work the fields
at home, and besides,
by keeping busy, I don't have
time to think about my problems.
In fact, I don't think
about anything at all.
That's good.
Incidentally, how is the
well coming along anyway?
Not too bad.
According to the schedule,
it looks like we should reach the
underground water vein in about one week.
Well, let's splurge on dinner tonight.
What do you say?
Wow, do you really mean it?
Thanks! Come again!
You know something, Meryl?
This place kind of
reminds me of my hometown.
But there's nothing here.
Your home is actually like that?
That's right.
It's just a quiet, plain,
ordinary little village.
But it was a great place to live,
because my whole family was there.
Oh, yeah, family.
Huh?
What is it, Meryl?
That man up there.
He's out there.
I know Knives is right out there.
The one I've been searching
for is so close, but...
Then just answer me one thing.
What in the hell do you intend to do
once you've actually found Knives?
Many years ago, he stole someone
who was very important to me.
So you want revenge?
I don't know.
I really don't know.
I see.
So that's how you live.
That's how you choose to live.
Wolf, what?
What am I supposed to do when I see him?
I actually killed a man with my own hand.
What could I possibly say to him?
I'm no different.
Ram. Ram.
I'm so sorry, Ram.
I did a terrible thing.
Now I'm a sinner too.
Vash?
What are you doing up here?
Your wounds haven't had
a chance to heal yet.
Oh, Vash, take it easy.
You shouldn't be out here.
You should be in bed.
I have to go. Go where?
Where are you planning
to go in that condition?
To Rim.
I have to go see Rim.
What?
What are you saying?
You're not making sense.
I have to go to where Rim is. I'm going.
Come on, you have to snap out of it.
You have to let us help.
Let go of me now I could never go
back I really killed someone I shot him
dead I Did I took his life but Vash
you didn't have a choice I'm ending
lives there's Always another choice
there had to be another way I just didn't
see it in time To do anything about
it Rem said so there had to be a way
Ram, please tell me, did I have…
Wait, Vash, you can't! Vash!
I don't know, Millie, maybe following
him wasn't such a good idea after all.
If we hadn't followed him,
he wouldn't have had
to make such a terrible
choice and things might
have turned out differently.
And then, he wouldn't have gotten hurt.
He wouldn't have had to suffer like this.
I just can't stand it.
You're wrong, Meryl.
The only reason you followed Vash is because
you care about him, isn't that right?
It could have happened anyway.
What's wrong with taking a stand
and acting with your heart?
Well, like my big, big sister always said,
never hold back in matters of the heart.
Gee, Millie.
Maybe you should be the one
that makes the decisions now.
Huh? Oh, nothing. Never
mind. Forget what I said.
All right, Millie.
We've got to keep going, so prepare
to work your butt off tomorrow.
Okay, Meryl!
Now, Vash, you take care of
the house while we're gone.
See you later.
Have a good day!
Since we've been taking care of him, Mr.
Vash looks a little happier
now, don't you think?
Yeah, you're right, he does.
Hey there, you're awfully late.
You can only say that because you're here.
Be glad.
You guys probably aren't aware of this,
but a whole lot of weird shit has
been going on around here lately.
Did something bad happen?
Mass disappearances in 12
towns with no trace of them.
L .R.'s one big war zone
and my family's missing.
I had no idea.
This is about the only peaceful town left.
There you go.
Hey, thanks a lot.
First time I've seen him.
Oh, yeah.
Two girls just showed up in town with him.
That was about ten days ago.
Poor fellow was in horrible shape.
Shot full of bullet holes.
It's amazing he survived.
Where have I seen him?
Come on, let's get out of here!
Huh?
What's up with the shouting, Simon?
Just get in the damn truck!
What's the rush?
Why are we leaving in such a hurry?
I must crash the stampede!
No question about it.
That one guy sitting there was
definitely the humanoid typhoon!
Ooooooooh!
So...
On the first evening a pebble.
From somewhere out of nowhere.
Drops upon the dreaming world.
So.
On the second celestial
evening All the children
of the pebble join hands
and Compose our waltz?
That's a nice song.
Hmm.
You can... Hmm?
You can stay here as long as you like.
That sounds good.
Might not be such a bad idea.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I didn't get very much sleep last night.
Meryl! Huh?
Meryl!
I'm gonna kill him.
I'm gonna kill that bastard.
Ha!
You really had us fooled.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't even bother playing dumb. Yeah!
How dare you bring someone like Vash
the Stampede here to endanger our home!
Don't say that.
We mean you no harm.
Listen, miss.
It's just that we don't want to die.
All we ask is that you leave
here and don't look back.
If you don't agree to
do that, you might die.
And now tell him what'll
happen to your friend!
That's enough!
What do you mean?
What'll you do to him?
No, you can't!
Stop!
You're hurting him!
Well,
did you feel some of
the pain of the people
who died because of
your reckless behavior?
What the hell's the matter with you?
Say something at least
make some kind of excuse.
Something's not right here.
Is it possible this guy
isn't him? Could be.
I never imagined that guy
to be such a wuss. I am.
What the huh?
I am.
I am. Him.
I'm Vash the Stampede. Huh?
You're right about me.
I'm...
I'm just...
nothing but a killer.
Don't get to fighting with me!
I've heard enough of your crying!
This is for everyone you've ever heard!
Now smile
At least you could have the decency to
die like a man, so come on you shit smile.
I Said smile damn it stop it please
You don't understand he fought to
protect everyone I beg you please
don't kill him He just came here to
heal he wasn't going to hurt anyone
Could a normal human being
to all those horrible things
He had to be the one!
Who else could have been responsible?
No, you're wrong!
Then tell me why.
Why the hell did Steven have to
die such a horrible death, huh?!
Answer me!
I've...
I've watched him for a
long time, so I know.
It's true that he can't avoid fighting,
but this man knows how to live.
To live like a decent human being.
Shooting him won't help anyone.
Don't feed me your garbage!
We have the right to shoot
this monster for everything.
He's done.
We lost friends families
Neighbors and even children.
We should hate this bastard,
and now he deserves to die
But you're wrong no one ever has the
right to take the life of another person
No one, no one ever has the right
to take the life of another.
No one, and everyone,
everyone deserves a future.
Oh, Rem.
Don't you think that's true?
Wait! Stay back!
Did you hear me?
I said stay back! Please.
Please, it's time to
stop the fighting now.
Why?
Why are you doing that?
Please get back!
It's up to us to end the cycle of hatred.
If we don't work to end
the sorrow this time,
then the cycle of pain
will just continue on.
When we were all born,
were any of us made to
steal or cause others harm?
That's it!
It's gotta be!
Hey, wait!
What are you doing?
People have many different
ways of thinking.
Even if a mistake is made,
as long as a person realizes their mistake,
it's possible to make it right again.
And if you keep your vision
clear, you will see the future.
This is what one must realize.
Right, Grandma?
I hate to ask, but how long
are you planning to do this?
Oh, this is a great day!
Let me go!
Let me go, baby! You forget!
Hey, I'm injured, remember?
The red flower Rem loved, the geranium,
and the language of flowers
means determination.
I made it again.
This one's yours.
You're going, aren't you?
Yeah.
I'm feeling a lot better now.
Don't worry, I'll be back.
be okay see you later good luck
Thanks and thanks for everything
I
want
you to take this with
you I know it would make mr.
wolf would happy in
fact it would Honor him.
Are you sure about this? I am.
Wow, this is pretty heavy.
Yeah, it is!
Of course it's heavy.
That's because it's full of mercy.
Well, take care of yourselves. Bye.
I couldn't...
I couldn't say anything to him.
Well, you can tell him
everything when he gets back!
You can go nuts on him!
I finally understand.
It was the last thing
she tried to tell me.
I will never go wrong again.
Humans are survivors, so
I will take care of him.
I'll save nights.
I'm not sure what's going on,
but I'm not sure what's going on.
That day, that time, 130 years
ago, we were born, weren't we?
There was nothing but peaceful days,
and Rem was always close behind us.
But our disagreeing thoughts changed
each of our ways of life, didn't they?
I don't regret it.
I will vow once again not to kill,
not to betray, but to find happiness,
to talk about my dreams, because the
ticket to the future is always blank.